{"tossups": [{"question": "Scholars have conjectured possible relatives of this man based on the fact that his last name means\u201cdeer\u201d in Narragansett. This man, who used the alias Michael Johnson, had been a slave of Deacon William Brown. This man\u2019s body lay in state in Faneuil Hall after men under Thomas Preston opened fire on a crowd that had been throwing snowballs. For ten points, name this Native American and African American patriot, the first person killed in the Boston Massacre.", "answer": "Crispus<b> Attucks</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {}, {"question": "Causes of this war included the execution of the crew of the<em> Virginius</em>. During this war, hundreds of soldiers died thanks to Russell Alger\u2019s cut-rate rations in the Embalmed Beef scandal. Frederic Remington was told to furnish pictures so that William Randolph Hearst could furnish this war, which was supported by yellow journalism. The sinking of the USS<em> Maine</em> helped trigger, for ten points, what war between the US and a European falling power in 1898?", "answer": "<b> Spanish-American</b> War", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "In 1947, this team\u2019s GM Billy Evans wrote \u201cTRUST YOU WILL FIND YOUR NEW CONNECTION A MOST PROFITABLE ONE\u201d in an antisemitic telegram telling Jewish-American star Hank Greenberg he\u2019d been given away to the Pittsburgh Pirates. In 1912, a player for this team shouted \u201cI don\u2019t care if he got no feet!\u201d when fans tried to get him to stop beating a handicapped man who had been heckling him; that player\u2019s career hits record was broken by Pete Rose. The notoriously racist Ty Cobb played over two decades with, for ten points, what Major League Baseball team in Michigan?", "answer": "<b> Detroit Tigers</b> (accept either or both names)", "metadata": "Trash - Trash"}, {"question": "This man was assassinated by Cassius Chaeraea after attempting to permanently move to Alexandria. This man may have gone mad after the death of Julia Drusilla, leading to rumors that he appointed Incitatus as a state official. This son of Germanicus was affectionately called \u201clittle boot\u201d by the legions. Tiberius was succeeded as emperor by, for ten points, what Roman emperor who supposedly made his horse a consul?", "answer": "<b> Caligula</b> (accept<b> Gaius Caesar</b>; accept<b> Gaius Julius Caesar Augustus Germanicus</b>; do not prompt on Caesar alone)", "metadata": "History - Ancient History"}, {"question": "During a visit to this country, one psychologist stated that his only goal was to \u201ccatch sight of a porcupine;\u201d that trip led Sigmund Freud to conclude that this country \u201cwas a mistake.\u201d A psychologist from this country developed the ideas of habit, will, and stream of consciousness in his book<em> Principles</em> <em>of Psychology</em>; that man also wrote the book<em> Pragmatism</em>. For ten points, name this home country of William James, who was a professor at Harvard.", "answer": "<b> United States</b> of America (or<b> US</b>A; accept<b> America</b>)", "metadata": "Social Science - Social Science - Psychology"}, {}, {"question": "The next day at this city\u2019s Lorraine Motel, James Earl Ray shot and killed the orator of that speech. Martin Luther King Jr. was assassinated in, for ten points, what second-largest city in Tennessee?", "answer": "<b> Memphis</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "This country, the only non-microstate in Europe that did not sign the Helsinki Accords, executed a priest for baptizing a child in 1971, four years after it declared itself the world\u2019s first atheist state. Hundreds of thousands of concrete bunkers were built in this country during the Cold War under Enver Hoxha, who replaced King Zog as its leader. For ten points, name this Balkan country where, in 1991, communism fell in Tirana.", "answer": "<b> Albania</b>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "This leader, who defined peace as \u201crespect for the rights of others,\u201d confiscated Catholic Church land in the Law of the Nationalization of the Ecclesiastical Wealth. This man\u2019s Minister of the Interior, Francisco Zarco, created the<em> rurales</em>, a mounted police force that was expanded by Porfirio Diaz. This man\u2019s family fled to New York after an invasion by Maximilian I, but he was restored to power in 1867. For ten points, name this Zapotec president who led the Liberals during the Reform War and opposed the French invasion of Mexico.", "answer": "Benito Pablo<b> Ju\u00b4arez</b> Garcia", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {}, {}, {}, {"question": "This politician published the autobiography<em> Why Not the Best?</em> shortly before declaring to run in the primary elections. During his term, this President oversaw the evacuation of Love Canal and the passing of the Superfund law. This man\u2019s namesake doctrine sanctioned the USSR for their invasion of Afghanistan, and he boycotted the Moscow Summer Olympics shortly before he lost re-election. The 2002 Nobel Peace Prize was awarded to, for ten points, what US President who was succeeded by Ronald Reagan?", "answer": "James Earl \u201cJimmy\u201d<b> Carter</b>, Jr.", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {"question": "At this location, the Marquis de Lafayette\u2019s willingness to kiss a queen\u2019s hand helped calm tensions during the October Days after cannons from the Hotel de Ville were dragged here by angry women protesting the price of bread. Charles Le Brun helped supervise the construction of this facility, which featured gardens designed by Andre Le Notre and a Hall of Mirrors. Paris was replaced as the site of the royal court by, for ten points, what French palace complex built by Louis XIV [14]?", "answer": "Palace of<b> Versailles</b>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}, {"question": "This agency changed its policies after an incident involving four year old Charlotte May Pierstorff. In 1970, this agency allowed its workers to be given collective bargaining rights after a nationwide strike involving 210,000 employees. People were forbidden to use this agency for obscene purposes by the Comstock Laws. Until 1971, the leader of this agency was a member of the Cabinet. For ten points, name this government agency for which Ben Franklin served as the first postmaster general.", "answer": "United States<b> Postal Service</b> (accept<b> USPS</b>; accept<b> US Mail</b>)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {"question": "A legend relates that these people came into existence after a namesake region revolted against Agis I. People born of these women were labeled as<em> nothoi</em>. An earthquake in the Eurotas Valley allowed these people to launch a revolt. Members of the<em> Krypteia</em> could kill these people without repercussions. These subjugated farmers made up the bulk of the population of ancient Laconia. For ten points, name this class of slaves in Sparta.", "answer": "<b> helot</b>s (prompt on descriptions of (Spartan) slaves)", "metadata": "History - Ancient History"}, {}, {"question": "After land mines and missiles were found at Ascot House, this man dismissed another leader as \u201ca cobra in the house.\u201d The Gukhurahundi massacres, whose name means \u201cthe early rain that washes away the chaff,\u201d were carried out by this leader\u2019s army. In the 2013 elections, this opponent of Joshua Nkomo claimed he would \u201cfight like a wounded animal.\u201d After sacking Emmerson Mnangagwa, this man was placed under house arrest. For ten points, name this leader of Zimbabwe from 1980 to 2017.", "answer": "Robert<b> Mugabe</b>", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {}, {"question": "This event led to the resettlement of 18,000 children in the Cuban resort town of Tarara. The Liquidators group was formed to bulldoze pine trees after this event, which required the building of a concrete sarcophagus. A high incidence of thyroid cancer was discovered among people in the vicinity of this event, which created the Red Forest. Pripyat was evacuated as a result of a failure in reactor 4 during, for ten points, what 1986 nuclear disaster in Soviet Ukraine?", "answer": "<b> Chernobyl</b> nuclear meltdown (or disaster, etc.)", "metadata": "Geography - Geography"}, {}, {"question": "<b>This man, who was accused of cannibalism in the Coffin Handbills, won a battle after the opposing soldiers forgot to bring ladders to climb the fortifications that this man had</b> <b>constructed. During that battle, this man was assisted by the French (+)</b> <b>pirate Jean</b> <b>Lafitte. This man defeated the Creek at Horseshoe Bend, the last battle of the Red Stick War, and he defeated Edward Pakenham in a battle that occurred (*) </b> after the Treaty of Ghent ended the War of 1812. For ten points, name this general who won the Battle of New Orleans before being elected President in 1828.", "answer": "Andrew<b> Jackson</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "<b>In this battle, the losing commander devised an attrition strategy known as Operation Judgement. To end this battle, Charles Mangin helped one side recapture a location that</b> <b>the losers captured without firing a shot on this battle\u2019s third day, (+)</b> <b>Fort Douaumont.</b> <b>Control of the Meuse Heights was a central goal of Erich Falkenhayn during this battle, which began roughly three months prior to the Battle of the (*)</b> Somme. The German plan to\u201cbleed [the French] white\u201d failed at, for ten points, what longest battle of World War I\u2019s Western Front?", "answer": "Battle of<b> Verdun</b>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "<b>A god from this civilization was syncretized with Hermes to form Hermes Trismegistus,</b> <b>the purported author of the Hermetic Corpus. While at this civilization\u2019s Siwa (+)</b> <b>oasis,</b> <b>Alexander the Great proclaimed himself to be a god. Worship of the syncretic god Serapis in this civilization was instituted by (*) </b> Ptolemy I, and worship of the sun disk Aten here was instituted by Akenaten. For ten points, name this civilization whose people worshiped the pharaohs as incarnations of Osiris and Horus.", "answer": "ancient<b> Egypt</b>", "metadata": "Mythology - Mythology"}, {}, {"question": "<b>This man attempted to secure power by forcing his nobles to swear the Salisbury Oath. This ruler\u2019s suppression of the revolt of Edgar the Aetheling was so destructive that the</b> <b>campaign became known as the (+)</b> <b>\u201cHarrying of the North.\u201d This man accounted for</b> <b>\u201cHarrying of the North.\u201d This man accounted for</b> <b>landholdings in his territory by ordering the compilation of the (*)</b> <b>landholdings in his territory by ordering the compilation of the (*)</b> Domesday [\u201cdoomsday\u201d] Book. The Bayeux Tapestry depicts the death of Harold Godwinson at the hands of this man\u2019s archers. For ten points, name this Norman duke who was crowned King of England after his 1066 victory at Hastings.", "answer": "<b> William I</b> of England (accept<b> William the Conqueror</b>; accept<b> William the Bastard</b>; accept<b> William of Normandy</b>; prompt on William)", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "<b>A message sent by William Draper to the overseer of this effort included a request for\u201cseventy Dakotas.\u201d After the success of this effort, a parade was thrown in New York City to celebrate Lucius (+) Clay. On a day called Black Friday, low visibility conditions saw an</b> <b>abnormal amount of participants in this effort fail to arrive on schedule at (*)</b> Tempelhof. \u201cRaisin bombers\u201d helped improve children\u2019s morale in, for ten points, what American supply effort that avoided a Soviet blockade of a divided German city?", "answer": "<b> Berlin Airlift</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "<b>Escalation in tensions before this war included a bombardment ordered by Lord Napier and a seizure of stockpiles by Charles Elliott. As a result of successful operations in this</b> <b>war, the name \u201cdevil ship\u201d was given to the iron warship (+)</b> <em><b>Nemesis</b></em><b>. During this war,</b> <b>Chusan and the Bogue Forts on the Pearl River Delta were captured. To end this war, the (*)</b> Daoguang Emperor accepted the Treaty of Nanking, granting Hong Kong to Britain. For ten points, name this 1839-42 war in China sparked by the trade of addictive narcotics.", "answer": "First<b> Opium</b> War (accept First<b> Anglo-Chinese</b> War) <b>Extra Question</b> Only read if you need a backup or tiebreaker! (1) <b>Art dealer Oliver Hoare was once seen entering the boot of this person\u2019s car.</b> <b>Controversy arose over this person\u2019s phone calls to James Gilbey, who nicknamed her</b> <b>\u201cSquidgy.\u201d This president for the Great Ormond Street (+)</b> <b>Hospital for Children</b> <b>supported philanthropy for AIDS and leprosy. Henri Paul was acting as security for this woman when her (*)</b> driver sped through the Pont de l\u2019Alma tunnel in 1997. For ten points, name this former wife of Prince Charles, a British princess who was killed in a paparazzi-triggered car crash. ANSWER:<b> Diana</b>, Princess of Wales (accept<b> Diana</b> Spencer; prompt on \u201cPrincess Di\u201d)", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {}], "bonuses": []}